### **RESUME**

# **Yogesh Kumar**

(Specialist Software Engineer)

D-13, Sukhdayak Society, J. B. Nagar, Andheri East, Mumbai - 59 9897303655 punyani.yogesh10@gmail.com

### **EXPERIENCE SUMMARY**

Backend Developer with 11+ Years of Experience in Various Domains and Technologies

Have worked on backend development using Core Java, Spring MVC, Hibernate, MicroServices, and Web Services.

Designed and implemented DB Architecture using Oracle and MySQL databases. Have deployed applications using Docker, Kubernetes, Open Shift, and AWS. Used GIT for version control and Jira for agile project management.

Have worked in various domains such as Telecom, Banking, and Health Care. A good team player who can collaborate and mentor junior team members. Always eager to learn new skills and technologies.

#corejava #Kafka #springboot #spring #mysql #rest #aws #agile #microservices #git

### **EXPERIENCE**

### **LTIMindtree** | Specialist - Software Engineering

September 2021 - Till Date Mumbai, India

- Tech stack: Core Java, Spring Boot, MicroServices, Unit Testing, Test Driven Development, Kafka, Spring Security, Hibernate, SonarQube, Agile, Bitbucket, IntelliJ Idea
- Senior developer of a Spring MicroServices Based application developed different REST API, different Modules.
- Consume the REST API provided by client using Retrofit Client and development different services Developed different services based on the different module.

# **Delta Technology and Management Services | Senior Consultant**

December 2016 - September 2021. Mumbai, India

- Tech stack: JavaScript, jQuery, Test Driven Development, HTML, CSS, Java, JDBC, Spring MVC, Spring Security, Hibernate, SonarQube
- Senior developer of a Spring Based application developed different modules like: User Module, Report Module.
- Developed Desktop Based Java Application with different types of file validations and given to the different Banks to validate their data and upload on web portal.
- Take decisions based on requirements, collaborating with senior solution architects, and providing effort estimation.

# **Experis IT Pvt. Ltd | Software Engineer**

July 2015 - May 2016. Gurgaon, India

- Tech stack: Java, Spring, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Amazon Web Services (i.e., Lambda, EC2, CLI, IAM), Oracle DB, REST API,
- Played a key role in architecting and developing and integrations with Third party API's and manage their documentations.

# **Artech Infosystems Pvt. Ltd | Software Engineer**

April 2015- July 2015. Gurgaon, India

- Tech stack: Java, JSP, JavaScript, React JS, Oracle DB, HTML, CSS
- Backend developer designs different modules and prepares documentations.

# **Cubic Web Solutions | Software Engineer**

June 2013 - Mar 2015. Noida, India

- Tech stack: Core Java, JDBC, Servlets, JSP, MongoDB, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery
- Junior backend developer on a yearlong Industrial experience with a focus on development of Java based application.

### **TECHINICAL SKILLS**

Language : JDK 1.8, 1.7, J2EE (JSP, Servlets), JDBC, Spring, Spring Boot, Microservices, Spring

JPA, Spring Batch, Hibernate, REST API

Databases : Oracle 11i, 10g, MYSQL5.5, Mongo DB
Web Tools : HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JSON, XML

Modeling Tool : IntelliJ Idea, Eclipse

**Application Server** : Apache Tomcat Server 9, Web Logic 10.3.6

Operating System : Windows 10, Linux, UNIX

Build Tools : Maven, Gradle

Testing Tools : JUnit, Cucumber

Message Queuing System : Apache Kafka, RabbitMQ

**Containerization** : Docker, Kubernetes

Cloud : Amazon Web Services (i.e., Lambda, EC2, CLI, IAM)

**Version/Integration** : Git, Jenkins, Bitbucket

# **PROJECTS**

#### **NETS Finland OY**

- Tech stack: Test Driven Development, Java, Spring Boot, Spring Security, Spring JPA, SonarQube, Maven, JSON. IntelliJ Idea
- Developed different Web based Rest API for different data.
- Worked on XML based services.
- Direct interaction with the client and understand requirement and provide solutions.
- Worked on middleware service between bank and Merchant.

# **PSD Development (IFX)**

- Tech stack: Test Driven Development, Java, JDBC, Spring MVC, Spring Security, Spring JPA, Maven, JSON,
   IntelliJ Idea
- Developed different Web based Rest API end to end for different data.
- Developed different services based on the user role and manage data based on Roles Design Database and different table and manage data.
- Documentation for Web Services Direct interaction with the client and understand requirement and provide solutions.

## **Automated Data Extraction Portal (ADEPT)**

- Tech stack: JavaScript, jQuery, Test Driven Development, HTML, CSS, Java, JDBC, Spring MVC, Spring Security, Spring JDBCTemplate, Hibernate, SonarQube, Maven, AJAX, JSON,
- Worked on Files Upload functionality of the application. Here users can upload files with Loan related data.
- User management functionality of application. Here creates users on different levels.

### My United Health Care (MyUHC)

- Tech stack: Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Gradle, Oracle DB, Test Driven Development, Docker
- An Application who has huge users list based of US, manage data of different Health related policies, Claim their medical related bills etc.

### **EMS (Expense Management System)**

- Tech stack: Core Java, JDBC, RESTAPI, Swagger Documentations, Mongo DB, HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- A system capable of helping companies to manage expenses in various areas like Business Expenses & Travel Expenses.
- Have integrated the EMS with other tools like: HRMS and SAP

### **EDUCATION**

# Uttarakhand Technical University | Master's in Computer Application (First class)

August 2010 - May 2013. Dehradun, India

**Activities:** Participated in various cultural activities like: - Dancing, Speaking.

# Chaudhary Charan Singh University | Bachelor's in Computer Application (First class)

August 2006 - May 2009. Meerut, India